Guide to the Marshall family papers, 1849-1898.
Marshall family papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Marshall family papers, 1849-1898.
128
Marshall family.
.3 cubic ft.
Correspondence and manuscripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscript books and letters on genealogy of the Marshall family.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscript books and letters on genealogy of the Marshall family, with the first record given as 898 in Normandy, thence through English history, pilgrim English, and pioneer American history, in Oneida County (N.Y.) and Windsor Connecticut; many collateral branches cited, including Henry Ward Beecher, Chief Justice John Marshall, General U. S. Grant, and the Griswold family.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Marshall family.; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885.; Griswold family.; Marshall, John.
Subjects:
Families -- Connecticut -- Windsor.; Families -- New York (State) -- Oneida County.; Pilgrims (New Plymouth Colony).; Pioneers.; Genealogy -- England.; Genealogy -- France -- Normandy.; Genealogy -- United States.; History -- England.; Families; Genealogy; History
Places:
Connecticut -- Windsor; England; France -- Normandy; New York (State) -- Oneida County; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- First "Book of Marshalls" of Edward C. Marshall, February 6, 1849 (Volume a)
  Beginning with Thomas Marshall, freeman of Boston 1634-1635. Collaterals: Griswald, Wilcox, Ward, Gaylord; copies of town records; assignment of Indian lands to Samuel Marshall, Windsor, Connecticut, 1663. Non-confornist Baptist Rev. Daniel Marshall, to Georgia in the early 1700s; Elijah Marshall in Montgomery's and Arnold's attack on Quebec in 1775 together with Captain Hanchett of Suffield, Connecticut being first to mount walls. First Marshall an adherent of Cromwell.
- Second Book of Marshall (Volume b)
  Genealogical notes by Edward C. Marshall; contains notes of English and Norman pedigree with English source books; back to Rollo, 898. Sketch of arms of Wards of England; Fifth cousinship to Rev. Henry Ward Beecher of Brooklyn; citations from early New England records; application blanks for Daughters of the American Revolution.
- Genealogical book of Edward C. Marshall (Volume c)
  Descendants of Marshalls of Windsor, Connecticut; Revolutionary records, collateral branches in Massachusetts and Connecticut' Yale graduates, 1742; Geneva College, 1843; loose notes; 4 sheets on Religious persecution in New England.
- Genealogical facts compiled by Adeline L. Marshall, Macoa, New York, 1891 (Volume d)
  Of the pioneer Andrew Ward, family; earliest member of the family given, Simon Ward, 1391, of Scotland; same family as Henry Ward Beecher.
- Letters of Anna Marshall Bellows of Gloversville, daughter of Hon. L.T. Marshall born Vernon New York, 1808, son of Levi (Harvey) Marshall of Winchester, Connecticut. Obituary clipping of L.T. Marshall., 1892 (Box e, Folder 1)
- Letters of Anna Marshall Bellows, Mrs. Morris Cushman, Mrs. Nellie B. Parkinson; sketch of Levi T. Marshall by son J.A. Marshall., January 9-May 15, 1893 (Box e, Folder 2)
- Letters from D.M. Marshall, Forestport, New York recording activities, character and descendants of Morgan Lewis Marshall; from Edward D. Griswald., August 16-December 21, 1893 (Box e, Folder 3)
- Letters of Anna Marshall Bellows and Nellie Parkinson, March 19-November 12, 1894 (Box e, Folder 4)
- Letters concerning David Heacock; letters of Anna Marshall Bellows from Washington, Georgis; from Seth Marshall, San Bernadino, California; from Appling, Georgia., 1895-1898 (Box e, Folder 5)
- Leaves from an old note book on Marshalls of Leyden, Holland and Kioke, Georgia and Baptist history. Notes on Nathan Higley family - descendent of Mrs. T.E. Bird, Cedar Rapids, Nebraska. Horace Higley on Morgan's staff in Civil War. Letter of Mrs. Josephine Herron, depositor (Box e, Folder 6)